What would you do if no one cared for you?
如果没人关心你，你会怎么办？
Imagine if you are honest about who you are,
想象一下，如果你向他人表现真实的自己
you could be killed
你可能会被杀
That's always been the reality for many LGBT folks
这一直是自美国建国以来
since the birth of America
许多LGBT人群所面对的现实
Many people lived in secret, fearful
许多人一生活都活在阴影中
that someone would discover their truth.
害怕有人会发现真实的他们
That was a motivation for Walt Whitman to write poetry
沃尔特·惠特曼的写作动机就在于此
沃尔特·惠特曼，1819~1892，美国诗人，有自由诗之父的美誉。
that would beckon gay people to save places
他的诗歌强有力地号召同性恋们
where they could build community.
联结属于他们自己的圈子
Yet most LGBT people were still forced to live in isolation.
然而大多数LGBT人士仍然被迫与世隔绝
Then Karl-Maria Kertbeny gave us the term
不久之后卡尔·玛利亚·克特本尼为我们提供了一个术语
卡尔·玛利亚·克特本尼，1824~1882，出生于奥地利的匈牙利记者，
回忆录家和人权运动家。他最著名的词是异性恋和同性恋。
homosexual in the power to identify.
同性恋——赋予了他们确认自己身份的权利
And writers like Alice Dunbar Nelson showed up
接着像爱丽丝·邓巴·纳尔逊这样的作家出现了
爱丽丝·邓巴·纳尔逊，1875~1935，美国诗人，新闻记者和政治活动家。
As a biracial bisexual woman,
作为一个双种族双性恋的女性
her courage in the face of prejudice allowed
她面对偏见的勇气帮助了
more stories of LGBT people to be told.
更多的LGBT群体讲出他们的故事
Like that of the two spirits, you need Native American We'wha
就像两种灵魂的共存，我们提到了威娃
威娃，1849~1896，来自新墨西哥州的祖尼族原住民，
著名的艺术家，曾担任过整个美洲原住民的文化大使。
who impressed President Grover Cleveland.
同美洲原住民一道散步给格罗夫·克利夫兰总统留下了深刻的印象
格罗弗·克利夫兰，1837~1908，美国第22和第24任总统。
But after her truth was fully known, she was villainized
但在她的秘密被公之于众后，她的名声受到了影响
Overtime LGBT people congregated in safe spaces,
长久以来LGBT人士聚集在属于自己的安全空间
and we began to see more representation in art, books and theater
但我们逐渐开始在艺术、书籍和戏剧中看到更多大胆的表达
America soon called women to fight
很快美国呼吁妇女们为自己而战
and a contingent of lesbians formed in the Women's Army,
不同性向的妇女们共同组建了一支队伍
which became a place where lesbian women could be themselves,
这为女同性恋群体提供了容身之所
After the war, many women refuse to go back to traditional gender norms
战后，许多妇女拒绝回归传统的性别范式
All of this paved the way for the homophile area for the first time,
这一切首次为同性群体的发声铺平了道路
we saw people publicly demanding livable communities and LGBT equality.
我们看到人们公开要求建设宜居社区和LGBT平权
Later, scientific studies prove that homosexuality
后来，科学研究证明同性恋
was not a psychiatric disorder
不是需要治愈的精神障碍
that needed to be cured and put an end to
并结束了把非异性恋群体
the practice of placing LGBT people in mental asylums.
安置在精神病院的做法
Well, there was a growing restlessness among gender nonconformists,
性别不合规者们日渐不满于安于现状
one by one. LGBT folks rose up to defend themselves,
性少数群体们接连站起来为自己辩护
rioting in places, like donut shops, cafeterias in bars.
在一些地方发生了暴乱，如甜甜圈店，酒吧的自助餐厅
Their courage sprung from Magnus Hirschfeld,
马格努斯·赫希菲尔德赋予了他们坚定的勇气
马格努斯·赫希菲尔德，1868~1935，内科医生和性学家，
曾经公开承认自己是同性恋者。
safe Haven for LGBT folks which inspired Henry Gerber
性少数群体们的避风港启发了亨利·格伯
亨利·格伯，1892~1972，美国早期的同性恋维权人士，
创立了德国最早的同性恋组织和美国最早的同性恋出版物。
to form the Society for Human Rights.
最终成立了人权协会
This motivated countless LGBT people to create,
这激发了无数LGBT人士的创造力
change and establish more LGBT organizations across America.
他们在美国各地改变和建立了更多的LGBT组织
By the time of Stonewall, it became impossible to
发展到石墙时期的时候，想要忽略同性恋解放运动
石墙暴动：
1969年发生在纽约石墙酒吧的暴力示威冲突，
被认定是美国史上同性恋者首次反抗政府实例，
是美国及全球同性恋平权的关键事件。
ignore the gay liberation movement.
变成了一件不可能的事情
Even the Rice leaders like Harvey Milk unapologetic Lee called for
甚至像哈维·米尔克这样的种族领导人也开诚布公地呼吁
哈维·米尔克，1930~1978，美国LGBT权利运动人士，
美国政坛中第一位公开同性恋身份的政治人物。
each of us to live fearlessly in the open.
我们每个人都应该无所畏惧地生活在自由和开放中
His murder and legacy inspired a new generation of civic activists,
他被谋杀的事件和他的遗志激励了新一代的公民活动家
1978年11月27日，哈维被射杀身亡。
fighting for the civil liberties of the LGBT people.
为LGBT人群的公民自由而战
In solidarity, LGBT people of all ages, races and genders,
他们为所有年龄、种族、性别的LGBT者提供声援
and their allies demanded equality for their community
他们的盟友在第一次全国同性恋权利游行中
at the first national gay rights march.
要求他们的社区平等
Then 1980s. How many calls gay cancer LGBT people
然后是二十世纪八十年代 众多患艾滋病同性恋者被归为癌症人群
with AIDS were denied healthcare.
他们不能享受医保
Many politicians were apathetic, those afflicted
政治家们对此无动于衷
hard to honest the will to survive against all odds
饱受折磨的患者们不愿面对生活的重重困难
while many in America refused to acknowledge this epidemic,
与此同时在美国还有人不承认该种病症
people got angry, sparking a movement that encouraged
群众被激怒了 他们浩浩荡荡发起一场运动
the community to act up when news revealed that
要求社会采取行动
AIDS affected even those who are not homosexuals,
直到艾滋开始影响圈外人时
policies finally began to shift.
政策才开始发生转变
By then, an entire generation had already disappeared,
自那以后，整整一代这一群体的人也就彻底销声匿迹
erasing many voices that carried our history.
承载着历史回忆的声音也就这样被抹掉了
Homophobia and transphobia led to the violent loss of more lives
对同性恋和变性人的恐慌引发众多暴力事件
as gay activists lobbied for protections already offered to other people.
同性恋狂热分子也纷纷游说当局以求得更好的保护措施
Then legislation criminalize discrimination against LGBT folks.
随即国家出台法案将歧视LGBT群体定为刑事犯罪
The military embrace gay Americans and did away with
军队欢迎LGBT群体成员参军入伍
'Don't ask, Don't tell'
并废除过去的“不说，不问”政策
为回避美国军队中同性恋的敏感话题，1993年时任总统克林顿定下此规定，
禁止军中谈论这一话题。
Gay couples gained the right to legally marry anywhere in the United States.
同性恋夫妇取得在美国任何地方合法结婚的权利
And now LGBT elders, like Marsha Wetzel are fighting and
类似于玛莎·韦策尔这样的老者
玛莎·韦策尔，1947~2020，促进了性少数群体的公平住房权益。
winning legal battles for housing rights.
也在积极争取房屋的财产权
Underlining that everyone deserves freedom from harassment
并强调所有人都不应受到歧视和侵犯
and discrimination, especially as we age.
尤其是那些由年龄和性别所造成的
Today, National Historic Landmarks recognize significant
当今 美国国家历史名胜清楚地认识到
LGBT events as part of America's history.
LGBT群体一事是美国历史的一部分
When faced with death and injustice, LGBT people were forced
当面对死亡和不公LGBT群体始终忍气吞声
to hide in the closet until the time was right to emerge as visible
直到时机成熟
and vocal activists for equality.
才有人为平等权利奔走呼号
Even today, in the face of rising hate crimes under representation in denial.
即便今天 为应对LGBT群体所受的日益严重的犯罪与厌恶 以及代表权利的缺失
LGBT people still struggle for acceptance and equality.
LGBT群体仍然坚持为获取普罗大众的认可和平等权作斗争
Three and four LGBT older adults still worry about having enough
三四位群体中的老人担心随着年龄的增长
support from family and friends as they age.
他们是否还会得到充分的支持
This fight continues and it's a fight where we all have a stake in.
这场纷争还在继续 我们也都牵扯其中
In the guiding words of AARP founders, Doctor Ethel Percy Andrus,
用美国AARP创始人埃塞尔·珀西·安德鲁斯博士的话来说
AARP：美国退休人员协会。
'What we do, we do for all'
“我们所做之事为的是所有人”
our movement that started as a fight
这场运动以一场抗争开始
for survival has become a story of resilience.
生存已经成为一个关于韧性的故事
This is progress paved by heroes in the past, present and into the future
这是英雄们在过去，现在和将来所铺就的道路
Now more than ever, it's time for all of us to stand up, speak out,
如今比以往更是时候让我们所有人大声疾呼
and claimed care for ourselves for our LGBT community, and for our future.
为我们LGBT群体呐喊 为了一个崭新的未来
由 AARP 支持的 LGBT 运动精彩历史
了解更多 aarp.org/PRIDE